physionet.org 2011-11-02

# PhysioNet Privacy Policy

**Your privacy is important to us.** We do not collect personally identifiable information on our web site or otherwise unless you choose to give it to us via an electronic mail message, a phone call, or by postal mail. Even when you choose to give us such information, we keep it confidential. 

**Mailing lists:** We do not sell, rent, share, or otherwise disclose mailing lists or other personally identifiable information. We maintain some records of individuals who contact us so that we may contact you later or provide further information to you in the future. We do not provide this information to anyone else unless you give us your permission. 

**Web server logs:** Our web servers collect information about dates and times when our web site was accessed, the IP addresses and host names of the computers that connect to our site, and the URLs of the web sites from which you linked to our site. We may use this information in summary form, stripped of personally identifiable information, to analyze web traffic and to document usage of this resource to funding agencies. 

**Cookies:** If you use the '-' or '+' controls (which condense or expand the page header) in the upper left corner of a page, your most recent choice is saved in a session cookie, so that page headers will maintain the appearance you have chosen as you navigate around the site. Within the PhysioNetWorks section of this web site, our server uses secure session cookies in combination with other authentication methods, such as passwords, to ensure that the source of uploaded content is correctly identified, and to protect restricted content from unauthorized access. PhysioNet does not use cookies elsewhere on its web site. 

**Registration:** If you wish to have access to any part of PhysioNetWorks, you must register as a member. _Registration is not necessary for access to any other part of the PhysioNet web site, including all of PhysioBank, PhysioToolkit, and the PhysioNet Library._

**Member profiles:** Registration requires you to create a member profile including your email address, full name, and country of residence. (You may provide additional information as part of your member profile, but this is optional). Your member profile is available to the owner of any PhysioNetWorks project you apply to join, and to other members of projects that you join. If you become the owner of a PhysioNetWorks project (either by your request or by your agreement to the previous owner's request), your member profile is available to all PhysioNetWorks members. Member profiles are not sold, rented, lent, exchanged, or made available for any other purpose. 

**About this policy:** Our privacy policy is based on those adopted by [Computer Professionals for Social Responsibility](http://www.cpsr.org/) and by the [Privacy Rights Clearinghouse](http://www.privacyrights.org/). This is a [P3P-enabled](http://www.w3.org/P3P/) web site. If you are using a P3P-enabled web browser, it should be able to fetch our P3P policy automatically. If not, here are our P3P policy and P3P policy reference files. 

Your comments and suggestions are welcome. We encourage you to use our [feedback form](http://physionet.org/cgi-bin/feedback) to comment on this page. If you would like to receive a reply, please send your comments by email to [ `webmaster@physionet.org`](mailto:webmaster@physionet.org?subject=http://physionet.org/privacy.shtml), or post them to: 

_PhysioNet  
MIT Room E25-505A  
77 Massachusetts Avenue  
Cambridge, MA 02139 USA  
_ |   
---|---  
  
Updated Thursday, 17 March 2011 at 10:41 EDT
